let's look at the solution to our disk
access time quiz we can ignore queuing
so a read of a randomly chosen bite
begins by seeking there the head
assembly is at one end of the dis a
randomly chosen bte will be at the
cylinder where we are or 999 cylinders
away or anywhere in between with equal
probability so on average we will be
seeking 500 cylinders away times 10
microseconds per cylinder so seek will
take us 5 milliseconds  at that point our
head is in a random place on the correct
track now we need to wait for the
beginning of the correct sector to get
under the head and just like when we
were doing the seek the rotational
latency will be on average half of a
rotation we will be lucky and land just
at the very beginning of the sector we
want sometimes we will be unlucky and
land just past the beginning of the
sector we want so we will not be able to
read that sector even though we are
technically right above the data we  want
to read we will have to  wait for the
beginning of the sector to get back
which is a whole rotation so on average
we will be having half a rotation each
rotation is a of a second or 10 m
sector sectors per track so the take
of rotation will be
m rotation 10 m in total will take 11
m to disk a